Guide to the Records of the Office of the Dean of Libraries (Carlton C. Rochell) RG.38.0.1.1
New York University Archives
Records of the Office of the Dean of Libraries (Rochell)
1949, 1960-2004
1980-1999
New York University Archives
New York University. Libraries
RG.38.0.1.1
24 Linear Feet in 24 record cartons.
This collection contains material associated with the administration of the Dean of Libraries, including materials related to research projects, events, and individual departments within New York University libraries.
Scope and Content
This collection contains the Records of Office of the Dean of Libraries from 1949, 1960 to 2004, with most of the materials dating from the 1980s and 1990s. The files are arranged by subject and include materials related to particular projects and departments of the New York University libraries, including library research guides, video production, technology, NYU in Albany, the Tamiment-Wagner Archives, online catalog, and the NYU-New-York Historical Society Partnership.
Related Materials
Records of the Office of Library Administration, Records of the Office of the Associate Dean of Libraries
Historical Note
The Dean of Libraries at New York University (NYU) oversees all of NYU's libraries; the NYU Press, which publishes more than 150 titles each year; and Campus Media Services. Carlton Rochell served as the Dean of Libraries for twenty-two years. Rochell is credited with helping to integrate technology into the NYU libraries and with developing a partnership between New York University and the New-York Historical Society to catalog and make accessible materials related to 18th and 19th century New York history. During Rochell's tenure, the library's book and periodical collections doubled, microfilm holdings tripled, the book endowment grew 1200 percent, and circulation of books and materials expenditures both tripled.
Access Restrictions
RESTRICTED - Administrative records and unpublished reports of New York University are closed for a period of 20 years from the date of their creation. Access to files spanning multiple years will be opened to researchers based on the date of the most recent materials. Board of Trustees records are closed for 35 years from the date of creation. Materials related to personnel, grievances, job and fellowship searches and applications, and all files that fall under the federal Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act (FERPA) are permanently restricted. Additional restrictions may apply to other materials in this collection. For questions regarding specific restrictions, please contact the University Archives.
Arrangement
Folders are arranged alphabetically by subject and then chronologically within each subject heading.
Files from the 2019 accretion were added to the end of the inventory in original order.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Transferred to University Archives from the Office of the Dean of the Libraries in 2014 and 2019. Accession numbers associated with these transfers are 2014.027 and 2019.009
Universities and Colleges -- Administration; Books.; Administrative records.; Job applications.; Reports.; Minutes (administrative records); New York University. Libraries; New York University. Office of University Development and Alumni Relations; New York University. Office of Budget and Resource Planning; Elmer Holmes Bobst Library; NYU Press; New York University. Faculty of Arts and Science; New-York Historical Society; Tamiment Library; Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives; New York University. Center for Advanced Technology; New York University -- History
- Adjunct Faculty Reappt's Summer FY02, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Conditions Governing Access note
  Restricted
- Administrative and Professional Position Description Questionnaire, 1981-1982 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- American Grassroots Political Activism, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- American Library Association (ALA) Code of Ethics, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Application—Activities Involving Human Subjects, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Application—Post World War II Immigrant Groups and Their Descendants in Western Europe, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Association of Research Libraries, 1997-1998 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Avant Guarde (Richard Schechner), 1983-1987 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Basic Documents I, 1971-1977 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Basic Documents II, 1971-1977 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Basic Documents III, 1971-1977 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Basic Documents IV, 1971-1977 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Blaufarb Agreement, 1992-1996 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Bylaws Revision, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Center for Advanced Technology (CAT) Multimedia, 1992-1994 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Center for Advanced Technology (CAT) Multimedia, 1995-1997 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Center for Advanced Technology (CAT) Multimedia Center Library of Congress, 1994-1996 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Center for Advanced Technology (CAT) Multimedia Technology Development Program, 1993-1996 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Center for Advanced Technology (CAT) Yiddish Theatre Brochure, 1997-1998 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Center for Research Libraries, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Chief Info Officer Search Committee, 1997-1998 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Coalition for Networked Info (CNI), 1993-1996 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Columbia/NYU Access Agreement, 1980-1996 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Complaints (Student & Faculty), 1985-1988 (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Complaints (Student & Faculty), 1989-1998 (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Compressed Video, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Confidentiality/Privacy, 1988-1991 (Box 1, Folder 27)
- Conflicts of Interest Policy, 1993-1996 (Box 1, Folder 28)
- Consortium, 1983-1996 (Box 1, Folder 29)
- Cooper Union, 1987-1995 (Box 1, Folder 30)
- Council of Literary Magazines and Presses, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 31)
- Council on Foreign Relations, 1990-1992 (Box 1, Folder 32)
- Courant Institute Library, 1988-1993 (Box 1, Folder 33)
- Culture of the Celt Spawns a Thousand Welcomes, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 34)
- Department & Unit Head Mtgs, 1980-1983 (Box 1, Folder 35)
- Department & Unit Head Mtgs, 1982-1988 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Department & Unit Head Mtgs, 1988-1998 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Development, 1982-1986 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Development, 1987-1998 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Development Activities Donors, etc., 1960-1993 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Development and Alumni Giving, 1980-1993 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Development Committee, 1975-1981 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Distance Learning, 1996-1998 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Diversity, 1988-1992 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Electronic Publishing, 1995-1999 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Faculty Meetings, 1988-1994 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Faculty Meetings, 1982-1986 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Faculty Meetings, 1987-1988 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Faculty Meetings, 1994-1997 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Faculty of Arts and Science, 1995-1998 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Faculty-Library Liaison, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Give a Violet, 2002 (Box 2, Folder 17)
- Institute of Fine Arts (IFA) Library, 1989-1995 (Box 2, Folder 18)
- Janice's Chrono File, 1978-1982 (Box 2, Folder 19)
- Laptops, 1995-1998 (Box 2, Folder 20)
- Libraries-General Information, 1973-1997 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Libraries-General Information, 1984-1991 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Library Research Guide, 1981-1998 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Library Sesquicentennial, 1960-1981 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- List of Donors, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Memoranda, 1981-1986 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Memoranda, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Metro, 1985-1999 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Micro Computer Center, 1989-1997 (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Micro Computer Center, 1990-1996 (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Micro Computer Center—SEHNAP, 1990-1991 (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Microcomputers, 1984-1986 (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Microcomputers, 1987-1994 (Box 3, Folder 13)
- Microforms, 1982-1988 (Box 3, Folder 14)
- Museum/Library Council, 1997-1998 (Box 3, Folder 15)
- Music, 1981-1985 (Box 3, Folder 16)
- Music, 1986-1991 (Box 3, Folder 17)
- Musical Theatre, 1981-1985 (Box 3, Folder 18)
- Musical Theatre, 1981-1999 (Box 3, Folder 19)
- National Initiative for a Networked Cultural Heritage (NINCH), 1997-1998 (Box 3, Folder 20)
- Network Printing, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 21)
- Networking/Technology, 1981-1993 (Box 3, Folder 22)
- New Media Centers, 1993-1994 (Box 3, Folder 23)
- New York Documentary Heritage Act Proposal, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 24)
- New York Historical Society (N-YHS), 1993-1994 (Box 3, Folder 25)
- New York Historical Society (N-YHS), 1995-1998 (Box 3, Folder 26)
- New York Historical Society (N-YHS), 1997-1999 (Box 3, Folder 27)
- New York Historical Society (N-YHS) Library, 1993-1994 (Box 3, Folder 28)
- New York Historical Society (N-YHS) Mellon Project, 1993-1994 (Box 3, Folder 29)
- New York Historical Society (N-YHS) Survey, 1997-1998 (Box 3, Folder 30)
- New York Public Library, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 31)
- New York State Research Libraries, 1981-1991 (Box 3, Folder 32)
- New York State Research Libraries Proposal, 1976-1986 (Box 3, Folder 33)
- New York Studio School, 1993-1994 (Box 4, Folder 1)
- New York University (NYU) Academic Computing Facility (ACF), 1995-1996 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- New York University (NYU) in Albany, 1997-1998 (Box 4, Folder 3)
- New York University (NYU) in Albany, 1997-1999 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- New York University (NYU) Press, 1995-1998 (Box 4, Folder 5)
- New York University (NYU) TV Sponsorship, 1994-1996 (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Newsletter, 1978-1999 (Box 4, Folder 7)
- NlightN, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 8)
- On-Line Catalog Evaluation, 1978-1994 (Box 4, Folder 9)
- On-Line Catalog Implementation, 1979-1988 (Box 4, Folder 10)
- On-Line Catalog PR, 1982-1997 (Box 4, Folder 11)
- On-Line Catalog Public Services, 1982-1988 (Box 4, Folder 12)
- On-Line Searching Dialog End User Services, 1990-1999 (Box 4, Folder 13)
- On-Line Study, 1981-1983 (Box 4, Folder 14)
- Organizational Review/Retreat, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 15)
- Orientation Staff, 1978-1986 (Box 4, Folder 16)
- Orientation Staff, 1982-1998 (Box 4, Folder 17)
- Performance Appraisal, 1977-1989 (Box 4, Folder 18)
- Personnel, 1991-1993 (Box 4, Folder 19)
- Personnel (1 of 2), 1991-1996 (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Personnel (2 of 2), 1991-1996 (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Personnel Discipline, 1989-1992 (Box 5, Folder 4)
- Personnel Review, 1989-1991 (Box 5, Folder 5)
- Personnel Search Committee Faculty, 1976-1992 (Box 5, Folder 6)
- Personnel Student Employees, 1980-1991 (Box 5, Folder 7)
- Pew Grant, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 8)
- Pew Grant, 1986-1988 (Box 5, Folder 9)
- Photo ID's, 1989-1997 (Box 5, Folder 10)
- Photocopy Center, 1984-1995 (Box 5, Folder 11)
- Preservation Committee, 1980-1998 (Box 5, Folder 12)
- President Oliva Plan, 1994-1998 (Box 5, Folder 13)
- Presidential Correspondence, 1993-1998 (Box 5, Folder 14)
- Problem Patrons, 1988-1998 (Box 5, Folder 15)
- Problem Patrons Brochures/Guidelines, 1984-1995 (Box 5, Folder 16)
- Procurement of Computer Systems, 1982-1994 (Box 5, Folder 17)
- Professional Librarian Faculty Status, 1972-1974 (Box 5, Folder 18)
- Public Relations/Press Releases, 1981-1993 (Box 5, Folder 19)
- Public Services Documents in Progress, 1982-1992 (Box 5, Folder 20)
- Public Services Service Policy, 1980-1984 (Box 5, Folder 21)
- Publications, 1985-1994 (Box 5, Folder 22)
- Real Estate Institute Library, 1982-1984 (Box 5, Folder 23)
- Real Estate Institute Library, 1984-1987 (Box 6, Folder 1)
- Real Estate Institute Library, 1988-1991 (Box 6, Folder 2)
- Real Estate Institute Library, 1990-1994 (Box 6, Folder 3)
- Real Estate Institute Library, 1991-1998 (Box 6, Folder 4)
- Recruitment Advertising, 1997 (Box 6, Folder 5)
- Ref 1/ILL Office Design, 1990-1991 (Box 6, Folder 6)
- Reference, 1988-1998 (Box 6, Folder 7)
- Reference Statistics, 1982-1983 (Box 6, Folder 8)
- Research Libraries Group (RLG), 1996-1998 (Box 6, Folder 9)
- Research Libraries Group (RLG) Archives and Museums Information System (AMIS), 1993-1994 (Box 6, Folder 10)
- Research Libraries Group (RLG) Digital Symposium, 1995 (Box 6, Folder 11)
- Research Studies, 1984 (Box 6, Folder 12)
- Science Center, 1983-1998 (Box 6, Folder 13)
- Security (1 of 2), 1977-1998 (Box 6, Folder 14)
- Security (2 of 2), 1977-1998 (Box 6, Folder 15)
- Sexual Harassment, 1995 (Box 6, Folder 16)
- Social Science / Docs Center, 1979-1996 (Box 6, Folder 17)
- Society for the Libraries, 1944-1967 (Box 6, Folder 18)
- Space Planning (1 of 3), 1992-1999 (Box 6, Folder 19)
- Space Planning (2 of 3), 1992-1999 (Box 6, Folder 20)
- Space Planning (3 of 3), 1992-1999 (Box 6, Folder 21)
- Space Undergraduate Library / Learning RES CTR, 1996-1997 (Box 6, Folder 22)
- Sponsored Programs, 1997-1998 (Box 7, Folder 1)
- Stacks, 1983-1997 (Box 7, Folder 2)
- Standards, 1975-1992 (Box 7, Folder 3)
- Statistics, 1990 (Box 7, Folder 4)
- Statistics, 1991 (Box 7, Folder 5)
- Statistics, 1991-1993 (Box 7, Folder 6)
- Statistics, 1992-1995 (Box 7, Folder 7)
- Statistics, 1993 (Box 7, Folder 8)
- Statistics, 1994-1996 (Box 7, Folder 9)
- Statistics, 1995-1996 (Box 7, Folder 10)
- Statistics, 1997-1998 (Box 7, Folder 11)
- Statistics, 1997-1999 (Box 7, Folder 12)
- Storage Offsite, 1990-1993 (Box 7, Folder 13)
- Strategic Plan (1 of 2), 1997 (Box 7, Folder 14)
- Strategic Plan (2 of 2), 1997 (Box 7, Folder 15)
- Strategic Plan, Implementation Reports, 1998-1999 (Box 7, Folder 16)
- Strategic Planning Teams, 1997 (Box 7, Folder 17)
- Street Fairs, 1985-1992 (Box 7, Folder 18)
- Student Library Groups, 1996-1999 (Box 7, Folder 19)
- Surveys, 1988-1998 (Box 7, Folder 20)
- Systems, 1984-1986 (Box 7, Folder 21)
- Systems, 1986-1991 (Box 7, Folder 22)
- Systems / Current, 1988-1989 (Box 7, Folder 23)
- Systems / Current, 1990-1998 (Box 8, Folder 1)
- Systems / HTML Liaisons, 1997 (Box 8, Folder 2)
- Systems Public Services, 1990-1992 (Box 8, Folder 3)
- Tamiment, 1986 (Box 8, Folder 4)
- Tamiment, 1984-1985 (Box 8, Folder 5)
- Tamiment, 1987 (Box 8, Folder 6)
- Tamiment, 1992-1998 (Box 8, Folder 7)
- Tamiment, 1991-2001 (Box 8, Folder 8)
- Tamiment-Wagner, 1998-2001 (Box 8, Folder 9)
- Tamiment-Wagner 250,000, 1985-1987 (Box 8, Folder 10)
- Tamiment-Wagner 250,000, 1969-2004 (Box 8, Folder 11)
- Tamiment-Wagner Archives, 1990-1992 (Box 8, Folder 12)
- Tamiment-Wagner Archives, 1988-1989 (Box 8, Folder 13)
- Tamiment-Wagner Dinner, 1986-1987 (Box 8, Folder 14)
- Taskforce on Electronic Texts, 1993 (Box 9, Folder 1)
- Technology BKRD Reports, 1992-1997 (Box 9, Folder 2)
- Technology Coordination Groups, 1997-1999 (Box 9, Folder 3)
- Technology Review (1 of 2), 1996-1998 (Box 9, Folder 4)
- Technology Review (1 of 2), 1996-1998 (Box 9, Folder 5)
- Telecommunications, 1986-1994 (Box 9, Folder 6)
- Teleconferencing (1 of 2), 1993-1998 (Box 9, Folder 7)
- Teleconferencing (2 of 2), 1993-1998 (Box 9, Folder 8)
- Telefacsimile, 1988-1997 (Box 9, Folder 9)
- Telephones, 1985-1995 (Box 9, Folder 10)
- Top Ten Reports, 1996-1999 (Box 9, Folder 11)
- T-Shirts, 1983-1986 (Box 9, Folder 12)
- Typewriters, 1984 (Box 9, Folder 13)
- Uncover Reveal, 1997 (Box 9, Folder 14)
- Union Contract, 1980-1987 (Box 9, Folder 15)
- Union Contract, 1983-1997 (Box 9, Folder 16)
- Union Strike Planning, 1988-1996 (Box 9, Folder 17)
- University Archives, 1984-1998 (Box 9, Folder 18)
- University Place Bookshop, 1996 (Box 9, Folder 19)
- Urban Study Group, 1988-1989 (Box 9, Folder 20)
- Urban Study Group, 1990-1992 (Box 10, Folder 1)
- Verdi Archives - RESTRICTED, 1976-1993 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  Conditions Governing Access
  RESTRICTED
- Video Production - RESTRICTEd, 1988-1990 (Box 10, Folder 3)
- Video Production - RESTRICTED, 1991 (Box 10, Folder 4)
- Video Production (1 of 2), 1992-1998 (Box 10, Folder 5)
- Video Production (2 of 2), 1992-1998 (Box 10, Folder 6)
- Video Production Center NYU-TV, 1990-1993 (Box 10, Folder 7)
- Video Production Center NYU-TV, 1993-1999 (Box 10, Folder 8)
- Video Production Center Satellite Dish, 1983-1986 (Box 10, Folder 9)
- Video Production Center Satellite Dish, 1987-1991 (Box 10, Folder 10)
- Video Production Center Satellite Dish, 1992-1993 (Box 10, Folder 11)
- Video Production Center School of Education, Health, Nursing and Arts Professions Continuing Education (SEHNAP) Agreement, 1990-1991 (Box 10, Folder 12)
- Video Production Center School of Education, Health, Nursing and Arts Professions Continuing Education (SEHNAP) Agreement, 1991-1996 (Box 10, Folder 13)
- Voice Mail, 1991-1993 (Box 10, Folder 14)
- Wagner Archives, 1992-1998 (Box 10, Folder 15)
- Wagner School, Civil Infrastructure Systems Inst, 1998 (Box 10, Folder 16)
- Word Processing, 1981-1987 (Box 10, Folder 17)
- Workers Compensation, 2002 (Box 10, Folder 18)
- World Wide Web, 1996-1998 (Box 10, Folder 19)
- Correspondence, Cost Allocation Reports, Sponsored Research Training Program Manual, 1981-1989 (Box 11, Folder 1-11)
- 2019 Accretion, 1949-2002; 13 Linear Feet in 13 record cartons.
  Scope and Contents
  A description of the document types and topical contents of the accession.
  See DACS 3.1.4-3.1.7
  Examples:
  Ten cartons of materials containing field notes, diaries, and drafts of maps documenting Mr. Smith's 10 years in residence at the Otay Mesa Ranch.
  This accretion contains administrative files organized by subject, generated by the Office of the Dean of Libraries from 1949 to 2001, with the bulk of the material dating from 1962 to 1998. File topics relate to specific projects and departments/institutions related to the office, including NYU Press; Graduate School of Business Library; online cataloging system; meeting minutes and notes for both the Dean's Council and Department and Unit Heads; user statistics; University Archives; Tamiment-Wagner Archives; and the New-York Historical Society.
  - GBA (Graduate School of Business) Library, Faculty Handbook, On-Line Catalog, 1965-1998; cuid3645 (Box 12)
  - Centers for Advanced Technology Program (CAT), Dean's Council, Internet Projects, Sponsored Programs, 1981-1997; cuid3646 (Box 13)
  - Special Libraries Directory, U.S. Legislation, ARL (Association of Research Libraries), GEAC Computer Corporation, RLG (Research Libraries Group, HEGIS Data Information System, 1975-1999 (Box 14)
  - Metro (New York Metropolitan Reference and Research Library Agency), Circulation Statistics, Consortium, 1978-1993 (Box 15)
  - Consortium, Courant Library, Department and Unit Heads Reports/Minutes, Disabled Student Services, 1977-2002 (Box 16)
  - GEAC Computers, Inc, Gould Library, IFA (Institute of Fine Arts) Library, Interlibrary Loan, Inventory, 1962-1996 (Box 17)
  - 1978 Library Master Plan, New School/Parsons, New-York Historical Society, 1967-1999 (Box 18)
  - New-York Historical Society, NYCRL (New York Comprehensive Research Libraries), Seward Park Project, 1992-1999 (Box 19)
  - New-York Historical Society, NYU Press, 1992-1999 (Box 20)
  - NYU Press, Organization, Photographs, Polytechnic Institute, Preservation of Library Materials, Requests, Research Carrels, 1963-1998 (Box 21)
  - Reserve Reading, Serials, Signage, Space, 1962-1995 (Box 22)
  - Space, Stern Move, Tamiment Library, 1962-1999 (Box 23)
  - Tamiment, University Archives, User Statistics, Video, NYU TV, Wenner-Gren Collection, Wiet Library, 1972-1995 (Box 24)